如果我对同一场景有两个视图，但视点有很大的变化，
If I have two views of the same scene but there is a very large change in the viewpoint,
我的相机的位置或方向，然后是模式的非常大的变化
a very large change in either the position or orientation of my camera, then the pattern
围绕这些兴趣点中的每一个的像素将是不同的。
of pixels that surrounds each of these interest points will be different.
例如，如果一个图像中拐角特征​​周围的像素图案看起来像这样
For instance, if the pattern of pixels around a corner feature in one image looks like this
如果我的第二个观点更倾向于那个特定的部分
and in the case where my second view looks more obliquely at that particular part of
那个世界，然后会给那个特定部分带来一些透视扭曲
the world, then that will introduce some perspective distortion to that particular part of the
图像和那两个窗口不匹配特别好。
image and those two windows will not match particularly well.
同样，如果我的相机远离场景移动，那么图像将会改变
Similarly, if my camera moves a long way away from the scene, then the image will change
在规模和我们使用的简单图像匹配技术也将失败。
in scale and the simple image matching techniques that we used will also fail.
而且，如果我旋转相机，图像相似性测量将再次失败。
And also, if I rotate the camera, again the image similarity measures will fail.
所以，我们需要的是一些方法来匹配一个兴趣点周围的区域
So, what we need is some way to match the region around an interest point that is in
缩放和旋转的变体。
variant to scale and to rotation.
现在，这是一个巨大的研究领域，今天有一些很棒的算法
Now, this is a huge area of research and there is some wonderful algorithms available today
提供此功能。
that provide this functionality.
也许，其中最着名的是DavidLowe的SIFT探测器在2004年倒退。
Perhaps, one of the best known is the SIFT Detector by David Lowe bended back in 2004.
并且，它提供类似的输出。
And, it provides output something like this.
这是我们之前看过的建筑物的图像，并覆盖在那里
Here is the image of the building that we looked at before and overlaid on that are
许多被称为SIFT功能的东西。
a number of what are referred to as SIFT features.
每个圆圈的中心代表一个兴趣点，一个足够明显的点
Centre of each circle represents an interest point, a point that’s distinct enough to
找到另一张图片。
find in another image.
位于每个兴趣点顶部的圆圈的大小表示某种东西
The size of the circle sitting on top of each of those interest points indicates something
关于功能的规模。
about the scale of the feature.
因此，围绕要素的圆圈中的所有像素都用于描述
So, all of the pixels that are in the circle around the feature are used to describe that
特征。
feature.
所以，我们可以看到一些功能非常小。
So, we can see that some features are very small.
它们包含大量密集纹理，分布在少量像素上。
They contain a lot of dense texture spread over a small number of pixels.
虽然，其他一些功能非常大，但它们涵盖了建筑物的整个角落。
While, some other features are very large, they encompass the whole corner of a building.
这些功能还可以对图像中要素的方向进行编码
These features also encode something about the orientation of the feature in the image
这是由径向线表示的。
and that’s indicated by the radial line.
我们将使用相同的图像快速查看这些比例不变和特征变换
We will have a quick look at these scale invariant and feature transform using the same image
我们在看Harris角落功能时使用过。
we used when we were looking at the Harris corner feature.
在这里。
And here it is.
现在计算SIFT功能我使用工具箱函数isift，我解析图像
Now to compute the SIFT features I use the toolbox function isift, I parse in the image
和我们用于Harris角落功能的非常相似的论点，我要去
and very similar arguments as we used for the Harris corner function and I am going
选择200个角落功能。
to select 200 corner features.
只需要一两分钟来计算，现在在工作区中我们有一个200SIFT的向量
Just take a minute or two to compute and now in the workspace we have a vector of 200 SIFT
点功能。
point features.
我们来看看其中一个功能。
Let's have a look at one of these features.
我们来看看向量中的第一个。
Let's have a look at the first one in the vector.
它被称为289.9和805.4的坐标，它有许多额外的属性，如
It's called a coordinate of 289.9 and 805.4 it has a number of additional attributes like
哈里斯的角落里有一种力量，表明这个特征有多么独特
the Harris corner it's got a strength which indicates how distinctive that feature is
但与Harris角落特征不同的是，它还具有方向，θ值以及
but unlike the Harris corner feature, it also has an orientation, a theta value and also
比例值。
a scale value.
我们来看看图像中的这个特殊功能。
Let's have a look at this particular feature in the image.
我们通过调用它的绘图方法来做到这一点，我们将用黄色绘制它，我要去
We do that by calling the plot method on it, we are going to plot it in yellow, I am going
夸大它的规模，所以它更容易看到。
to exaggerate it's scale so it's a bit easier to see.
我会将比例夸大16倍，我将以时钟格式显示它
I will exaggerate the scale by a factor of 16 and I am going to display it in clock format
我会在片刻解释一下。
and I will explain that in just a moment.
我们看到了这个功能。
There we see the feature.
围绕它绘制一个圆圈，圆圈表示特征的比例和
Drawn a circle around it and the circle indicates something about the scale of the feature and
作为时钟之手的线是时钟选项的意思
the line which is the hand of the clock it's what the clock option is about says something
关于特定功能的方向。
about the orientation of the particular feature.
现在我们可以显示整个图像的SIFT功能。
Now we can display the SIFT features for the whole image.
要做到这一点，我将重新显示原始场景，使它更暗，然后我
To do that, I am going to redisplay the original scene draw it a little darker and then I am
将绘制白色的所有功能，我们夸大了这个规模
going to plot all of the features in white and we exaggerate the scale a bit less this
时间，我将它们显示为时钟。
time and I am going to display them as clocks.
在那里我们看到它。
And there we see it.
每个要素都有一个坐标，即图像中的一个点。
Each feature has a coordinate, a point within the image.
对于每个特征，我们围绕它绘制一个圆圈，圆圈的大小表示某些东西
For each feature we draw a circle around it and the size of the circle indicates something
关于功能的规模。
about the scale of the feature.
一个小圆圈表示一个非常小的像素模式
A small circle indicates a pattern of pixels that's quite distinct across that very small
图像中的空间尺度。
spatial scale within the image.
所以它可能是一片叶子，它可能是阳台的一个小角落或窗户
So it might be a single leaf, it might be a small corner of a balcony or a window in
图片。
the image.
大圆对应于大规模特征。
A large circle corresponds to a large scale feature.
所以这可能是一个特别大的特殊尺度
So that's something that is distinctive at a much larger special scale so it might be
一个明亮的建筑的总体思路，沿着底部边缘的一些黑暗的树木包围。
the general idea of a bright building surrounded by some dark trees along the bottom edge.
功能的位置也有很多信息。
There is a lot of information in the position of the feature also in its scale.
每个圆都有一条径向线，对应于圆的方向
Each circle has got a single radial line and that corresponds to the orientation of the
该功能正在说明像素模式是如何定位的
feature that is saying something about how that pattern of pixels is oriented within
图片。
the image.
想象一下，现在我有点戏剧性地移动相机。
Imagine now I move my camera somewhat dramatically.
也许我把它旋转了90度，或者我离建筑物更远了。
Perhaps I rotated it by 90 degrees or perhaps I moved much further away from the building.
SIFT功能的巨大优势在于它可以让我在两者之间进行匹配
The great advantage of the SIFT feature is that it will allow me to match features between
这两种截然不同的观点。
these two very different views.
尽管场景中像素图案的方向虽然不同
Although the orientation of the pattern of pixels in the scene will be different although
像素模式的比例会有所不同，SIFT算法能够看到
the scale of the pattern of pixels will be different, the SIFT algorithm is able to see
通过那个。
through that.
你会在两个截然不同的观点中找到同样有趣的观点。
And you will find the same interesting point in each of the two very, very different views.
但我们会报告方向已更改或功能的规模
But we will report that the orientation has changed or that the scale of the feature has
改变。
changed.
除了具有位置，方向和比例之外，SIFT特征还具有描述符
In addition to having a position and an orientation and a scale the SIFT feature also has a descriptor
我们可以看一下第一个特征的描述符。
and we can have a look at the descriptor for feature number one.
我们可以在工作区中看到新变量D，它是一个128元素向量。
And we can see here in the workspace the new variable D and it is a 128 element vector.
SIFT算法描述了圆圈内的像素模式，我们称之为
The SIFT algorithm describes the pattern of pixels within the circle, what we call the
128元素向量支持区域。
support region by 128 element vector.
所以这是对该特定像素模式的全面描述。
So that's quite a comprehensive description of that particular pattern of pixels.
如果我们对同一场景有两个非常非常不同的视图，即使是方向
If we have two these very, very diverse views of the same scene even though the orientation
而且规模可能非常非常不同。
and the scale might be very, very different.
与两个场景中的兴趣点相关联的描述符将非常非常
The descriptors associated with the interest points in the two scenes will be very very
类似，我们可以简单地评估这两个场景之间的点的相似性
similar and we can evaluate the similarity of points between these two scenes simply
通过比较他们的两个描述性向量，通常是在欧几里德式中完成的
by comparing their two descriptive vectors and typically that's done in the Euclidian
通过两个方差之差的平方和的平方根感
sense by the square root of the sum of the squares of the difference between the two
描述性载体。
descriptive vectors.
现在，这是对SIFT功能概念的一个非常粗略的介绍。
Now this has been a very cursory introduction to the idea of SIFT features.
不幸的是，在这个入门课程中，计算机视觉非常重要，
The very very important in computer vision unfortunately in this introductory course,
我不可能对此有更多的说法。
it's not possible to say very much more about this.
有很多文献，你会在许多计算机视觉教科书中找到它们。
There is a lot of literature and you will find mention of them in many computer vision text books.